Fred W. Householder papers, 1945-1994 C450
Indiana University Archives
- Publications, reviews, and writings, 1940-1993 (Box 7)
  - Reviews, 1954-1987 (Box 9)
    - "Acoustical Characteristics of Selected English Consonants," by Ilse Lehiste, 1965 (Box 9)
    - "O.S. Akhmanova", 1965 (Box 9)
    - "Proceedings of the Fourth International Congress of Phonetic Sciences" by Helsinki, 1965 (Box 9)
    - "Trends in Modern Linguistics", 1965; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - "Language and Style," by Stephen Ullmann, 1966 (Box 9)
    - "In Memory of J.R. Firth", 1968 (Box 9)
    - "Abstract Syntax and Latin Complementation," by Robin T. Lakoff, 1969 (Box 9)
    - "Greek particles in Helenistic prose" by Jerker Blomqvist, 1969 (Box 9)
    - "Language and its Structure," by R.W. Langacker, 1969 (Box 9)
    - "Review of Encyclopedia of Linguistics, Information and Control", 1970 (Box 9)
    - "The State of the Art", 1970 (Box 9)
    - "Lucien, Le Navire ou les Souhaits," by G. Husson, 1971 (Box 9)
    - "The Study of Syntax," by D.T. Langendoen, 1971 (Box 9)
    - "Essential of English Grammar," by D.T. Langendoen, 1972 (Box 9)
    - "Progress in Linguistics," ed. Bierwisch and Heidolph, 1972 (Box 9)
    - "Greek: A Survey of Recent Work", 1973 (Box 9)
    - "Linguistics at Large," N. Minnis edition, 1973 (Box 9)
    - "Cypriot Greek," by B. Newton, 1974 (Box 9)
    - "The Formal Analysis of Natural Languages", 1974 (Box 9)
    - "Inflectional Morphology," by P.H. Mathews, 1974 (Box 9)
    - "Linguistic Changes and Generative theory", 1974 (Box 9)
    - "Lexicography in English", 1975 (Box 10)
    - "Selected Writings," by Kenneth L. Pike, 1975 (Box 10)
    - "Declinatio: A Study of Linguistic Theory of Marcus Terentius Varro," by Daniel Taylor, 1976 (Box 10)
    - Chariton by Gareth L. Schmeling, 1978 (Box 10)
    - "Studies in the Sytax of the Verbal Noun in Early Latin," by Rosen Hannah, 1981 (Box 10)
    - The History of Linguistics in the Classical Period by Daniel Taylor, 1987; (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - "Lucien écrivain, imitation etc. Creation" by J. Bompaire, undated (Box 10)
    - "Studies in Modern Greek I: Greek Spelling" by Kostas Kazazis (Box 10)
    - "Universals," by J. Greenberg, undated (Box 10)
- Teaching Files, 1954-1969 (Box 10)
  - Classical Grammarians and Panini, 1954-1969 (Box 10)
  - Comments and an Experiment Testing Vocalic Duration in French by Steve Disraeli, Spring 1967 (Box 10)
  - Contreras, Heles, Spanish, undated (Box 10)
  - Greek exam and student information, undated (Box 10)
  - John M. Howie's Dissertation Outline: Mandarin, undated (Box 10)
  - Kumiko problem, student file, undated (Box 10)
  - Lakoff's Thesis and some notes, undated; (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Latin (Box 10)
    - 1st paper, 1960 (Box 10)
    - 2nd paper, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Stuff, student papers (2 of 2,), undated (Box 10)
  - Linguistics (Box 10)
    - Classics, L 533, student papers, undated (Box 10)
    - Seminar materials, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Lucian (Box 10)
    - General, undated (Box 10)
    - Inscriptions (Columbia University), undated (Box 10)
    - Translation, undated (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Student work, June 25, 1959 (Box 10)
    - Student Papers, 1967-1969 (Box 10)
    - Language hand-outs, undated (Box 10)
  - Sanskrit (Perry,), undated (Box 10)
  - Shiriana (Irish Tape), June 1963 (Box 10)
  - Spanish Phonetics (425) Campbell & Students, December 1968 (Box 10)
  - Stockholm, undated (Box 10)
  - Swadesh 100-word list for 5 IE languages, starting with Latin: worksheet, undated (Box 10)
  - Taurepan, undated (Box 10)
  - Thai, McLaughlin's Paper, undated (Box 10)
  - Transcribing Language: Shiriana, undated (Box 10)
  - Usarufa (Territory of New Guinea) tape/ Indonesian text and U. Raffler tapes, undated (Box 10)
  - Workshops, 1954-1955 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1945-1989 (Box 10)
  - "A", 1959-1969; 1984 (Box 10)
  - "B", 1955-1986 (Box 10)
  - Bazell, C.E., 1954-1970 (Box 10)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, undated (Box 10)
  - Bolinger, (Dwight-Harvard University), undated (Box 10)
  - "C", 1957-1980 (Box 10)
  - Cambridge Press, undated; (7 folders) (Box 10)
  - Cambridge Press, Wilson (Black, Allen) Case etc., undated (Box 10)
  - Center for Applied Linguistics committee on Contrastive Latin and English, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
  - Colorado (University of), 1969-1975 (Box 10)
  - "D", 1959-1982 (Box 10)
  - "E", 1958-1984 (Box 10)
  - "F", 1957-1985 (Box 10)
  - "G", 1960-1985 (Box 10)
  - General, 1962-1989; (7 folders) (Box 11)
  - Greek Correspondence (Box 11)
    - 1953-1964 (Box 11)
    - 1965-1970 (Box 11)
  - Gunter, Richard, 1962; 1974 (Box 11)
  - "H", 1956-1982 (Box 11)
  - Hymes, Dell, 1954-1960 (Box 11)
  - "I J", 1955-1989 (Box 11)
  - "K", 1960-1986 (Box 11)
  - Koutsoudas, Andreas, undated (Box 11)
  - "L", 1956-1986 (Box 11)
  - Last letter on Reader: Readings in Linguistics I, undated (Box 11)
  - Linguistic Society of America, 1967-1969; (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Linguistic Society of America Nomination Committee, 1961-1972 (Box 11)
  - Lyons, John, undated (Box 11)
  - "M", 1957-1986 (Box 11)
  - Machine Translation and Computational Linguistics Association (MT Society), undated (Box 11)
  - "Mc", 1957-1971 (Box 11)
  - "N", 1959-1973 (Box 11)
  - "O", 1960-1968 (Box 11)
  - "P Q", 1956-1986; (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Penguin Letters, undated (Box 11)
  - Penguin Reader, undated (Box 11)
  - G.P. Putnam's son, 1945; 1955 (Box 11)
  - "R", 1960-1971 (Box 11)
  - Rice, Lester A., 1967 (Box 11)
  - "Sa-Sp", 1956-89; (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - "Sq-Sw", 1960-1971 (Box 11)
  - "T", 1959-1974 (Box 12)
  - Taylor, John E., 1973 (Box 12)
  - Thorne, J.P., 1962-1972 (Box 12)
  - "U V", 1959-1972 (Box 12)
  - "W", 1957-1984 (Box 12)
  - Word Newsletters/Correspondence, 1937-1975 (Box 12)
  - "X Y Z", 1960-1974 (Box 12)
- Subject files, 1946-1994 (Box 12)
  - Anthropology and Sociology, undated (Box 12)
  - Bibliography (Box 12)
    - Logic and Language, 1969-1970 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 12)
    - undated (Box 12)
  - Bibliography and exam for history of Linguistics, undated (Box 12)
  - Birthday responses, for 65th, undated (Box 12)
  - Carolyn Orr's Kichua Texts, undated (Box 12)
  - Equipment, 1965-1967 (Box 12)
  - Faculty Annual Reports work load, undated (Box 12)
  - Felicitous Insincerities, undated (Box 12)
  - Forms, undated (Box 12)
  - Harvard (language materials,), undated (Box 12)
  - Hawaii, Linguistic Department, 1971-1973 (Box 12)
  - Honors, undated (Box 12)
  - IU Linguistics Club, 1968; 1975; 1977 (Box 12)
  - The I.T.R. (The Institutionalized Tertiary Response,), undated (Box 12)
  - Linguistic Institutes, undated (Box 12)
  - Linguistic Society of America by Linguistic Society of America, 1924-, 1924-1999 (Box 12)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Math puzzle, undated (Box 12)
  - Memorial, 1994 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - General (Box 12)
      - 1946-1948 (Box 12)
      - 1959, 1968 (Box 12)
    - Addresses, undated (Box 12)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 12)
    - Materials, undated (Box 12)
    - Transcription, undated (Box 12)
  - National Science Foundation, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Neo-Latin Lexicography, 1955-1957 (Box 12)
  - Old Curriculum Vitae and Bibliography, undated (Box 12)
  - Ph.D. Linguistic Candidates, undated (Box 12)
  - Phonetics Lab, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Programs of Meetings (Box 12)
    - 1955-1962 (Box 12)
    - 1961-1980 (Box 12)
  - Reappointment and Promotion, Tenure, undated (Box 12)
  - Riebel, David "Indirect Discourse in Genesis", undated (Box 12)
  - Scientific Advisory Board – Committee on Mechanical Translation, 1962 (Box 12)
  - Signrd's workbook, undated (Box 12)
  - Teaching: Dissertations, undated (Box 12)
  - Thesis and Gallaway notes, University of Vermont, Burlington, undated (Box 12)
  - Uralic committee, 1960; 1962 (Box 12)
  - Concordances, undated (Box 13)
  - Restricted files (Box 14)